Finding aid for the Old Lesbians Organizing for Change records SSC.MS.00671
Sophia Smith Collection
- Administrative files, 1987-2018; 1
  - Alphabetical files, 1987-2008; B
    - National Gay and Lesbian Task Force (NGLTF), 1999 (Box 7)
    - National Gay and Lesbian Task Force conference, 1991-1992 (Box 7)
    - National Gay and Lesbian Task Force correspondence, 1993-1996 (Box 7)
    - National Gay and Lesbian Task Force leaflet, undated (Box 7)
    - Non-contributors, 1995-1996; undated (Box 7)
    - Non-discrimination policy, 1992-1998 (Box 7)
    - Non-profit exemption, 1992-1998 (Box 7)
    - OLOC norms, 1991-1992; undated (Box 7)
    - Oral Herstory flyer, undated (Box 7)
    - Oral Herstory Project training manual, undated (Box 7)
    - Organizing local OLOC groups, 1993-1995; undated (Box 7)
    - Orientation packet, 1995 (Box 7)
    - Overseas letter, 1995 (Box 7)
    - Overviews on ageism, undated (Box 7)
    - Older Women's League (OWL) materials, 1993-1996; undated (Box 7)
    - Older Women's League (OWL) newsletters, 1996 (Box 7)
    - Esther Pashek, 1996 (Box 7)
    - OLOC planned giving, undated (Box 7)
    - Planned giving brochures, undated (Box 7)
    - Pledge card, 1996 (Box 7)
    - Policy statement, 1995 (Box 7)
    - Postal permits, 1994-2000 (Box 7)
    - P.O. permit- Minneapolis, 2003 (Box 7)
    - Racism workshop, 1999 (Box 7)
    - OLOC regional organizing, 1991-1992; undated (Box 7)
    - Reimbursements, 1992-1995; undated (Box 7)
    - Resignation, 1999 (Box 7)
    - Pat Rutherford, undated (Box 7)
    - Sales tax certificates, undated (Box 7)
    - OLOC's single issue, undated (Box 7)
    - State contact- multiple, undated (Box 7)
    - State contacts, 1997-1998; undated (Box 7)
    - State contact- single, undated (Box 7)
    - Storage contract, 2003 (Box 7)
    - Subscription renewal, 1997 (Box 7)
    - Tax-exempt: locals, 1999 (Box 7)
    - Trademark, 2003; undated (Box 7)
    - Transsexuals, 1992-1995 (Box 7)
    - Travel directory master, 1997-2001 (Box 7)
    - Uncommon Legacy Foundation, 1999 (Box 7)
    - Website, 1996-2004 (Box 7)
    - Welcoming congregations, 1996; undated (Box 7)
    - White Privilege, 1988-1993 (Box 7)
  - Financial records, 1990-2008; C
    - Financial, contributions, and tax records, 1990-2007 (Box 8, Box 9)
    - Astraea Grant, 1996-2000 (Box 9)
    - Bunnies on the Bayoy, 1999-2001 (Box 9)
    - Hollyfield Foundation Grant, 2002 (Box 9)
    - Legacy Grant, 1996-1999 (Box 9)
    - Uncommon Legacy Grant, 2003 (Box 9)
    - General Grants, 2004-2008 (Box 9)
    - Elizabeth Stevenson Will, 2000 (Box 9)
  - Newsletters, 1990-2010; D
    - Newsletters, 1990-2010 (Box 10, Box 11)
    - Drafts, interviews, and mailing lists, 1992-1994 (Box 11)
  - Publications, 2000-2008; E
    This sub-series includes collected publications, newsletters, news clippings, and reports. The publications are a mix of press about the Old Lesbian Organizing Committee and resources saved for distribution to members about aging and old lesbians.
    - Publications and Resources, 2000-2005 (Box 13)
    - Press and News Clippings, 1993-2008 (Box 13, Box 20)
  - Steering Committee records, 1989-2017; F
    - Steering Committee meeting minutes and membership lists, 1989-2017 (Box 12, Box 13)
    - Steering Committee Applications, 2000-2003 (Box 13)
    - Susan Wiseheart OLOC digital files, 2007-2018; 1 items (1 flash drive); 0.19 Gigabytes (387 files) (Box 28)
      Susan Wiseheart's files dating from when she began as a Administrative contract worker for OLOC in 2007 until 2018. The contents includes Steering Committee and Board of Directors records (minutes, reports, handouts, resolutions); OLOC chapter records; articles and images for for various forms of media (OLOC Reporter, E-News, website); speeches, presentations, photos and planning documents related to OLOC gatherings and other events (see complete file list for more detail).
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      This content accession consists entirely of materials in digital form that are not currently available online. Please consult with Special Collections staff to request access to this digital content.
    - Steering Committee video recordings, 2007; 13 items (4 DVDs and 9 Mini DV tapes) (Box 28)
  - Collected Video Recordings, 1990-2008; G
    This file includes tv programs, documentaries, and talks that relate to OLOC activities, members, or general information of aging and LGBT identities.
    - QTV Pat R. 9-98 Voices from Our Elders, 1998; 1 items (1 VHS tape) (Box 26)
    - #7 "Acting Our Age" video which includes Shevy Healey, 1 items (1 VHS tape) (Box 26)
    - MOW-OLOC Chevy, Song, Holmes and Diaz, 1 items (1 VHS tape) (Box 26)
    - Golden Threads, 1 items (1 VHS tape) (Box 27)
    - Bridging the Generations Vera Martin, 1992; 1 items (1 VHS tapes) (Box 27)
    - An Uncommon Legacy Fund Sixth Annual Extra Mile Award, 2001; 1 items (1 VHS tape) (Box 27)
    - U of H Women's Studies Program presents: Lesbian Activism 70s and 80s, 2001; 1 items (1 VHS tape) (Box 27)
    - Voicing the Legacy Directed by Eleanor Savage, 2 items (2 VHS tape) (Box 27, Box 29)
    - Aging and You New York State Office for the Aging, 1992; 1 items (1 VHS tape) (Box 27)
    - Mornings on 2 Interview w/ Vera Martin 3/23/94, 1994; 1 items (1 VHS tape) (Box 27)
    - Kyro News #7 7/9/90 Senior Citizens- Growing Older in Today's Society, 1990; 1 items (1 VHS tape) (Box 27)
    - Bump! Episode #15: Houston, TX, 1 items (1 VHS tape) (Box 27)
    - The Del Martin Old Lesbian Pride Award, 1 items (1 DVD) (Box 28)
    - Jean Mtgrv interview on Radio Oct 98, 1998; 1 items (1 CD) (Box 28)
    - Program about OLOC run/produced by "Women's Magazine" on KPFA 94.1, 2008; 1 items (1 CD) (Box 28)
- Gatherings, 1995-2014; 2
  This series is arranged chronologically, with undated workshop plans at the end of the series.
  Biographical / Historical
  In 1996, OLOC held its first National Gathering, bringing together Old Lesbians from coast to coast, at the University of Minnesota in Minneapolis. Hundreds of Old Lesbians gathered in San Francisco, California in 1999. In 2002, OLOC held its third Gathering, again in Minnesota. Old Lesbians at the Gatherings expressed a strong desire for more frequent opportunities to get together, so the schedule was switched from once every three years to every other year. Since 2002, the group has met every two years on even-numbered years.
  This series contains materials related to the annual Summer Gathering, including video and audio recordings, preparation materials, workshop plans, programs, correspondence, presenter bios, and publicity.
  - 1996 Gathering, A
    - Articles (Box 14)
    - Attendee list (Box 14)
    - Banquet/dance tickets (Box 14)
    - Budget (Box 14)
    - Call for art (Box 14)
    - Committee minutes (Box 14)
    - Conference call (Box 14)
    - Correspondence (Box 14)
    - Decals (Box 14)
    - EI (Environmental Illness) Information (Box 14)
    - Evaluations (Box 14)
    - Final reports (Box 14)
    - Flyer for Gathering (Box 14)
    - Housing (Box 14)
    - Masters for Gathering (Box 14)
    - Panel correspondence (Box 14)
    - Planning Committee, 1995-1996 (Box 14)
    - Presentation texts (Box 14)
    - Presenters (Box 14)
    - Presenters' bios (Box 14)
    - Press releases (Box 14)
    - Program (Box 14)
    - Program ads (Box 14)
    - Program/agenda (Box 14)
    - Program book (Box 14)
    - Publicity (Box 14)
    - Reading list (Box 14)
    - Registrants acknowledgment (Box 14)
    - Registration forms (Box 14)
    - Reports/evaluations (Box 14)
    - Room names (Box 14)
    - Scholarships (Box 14)
    - Steering Committee bios (Box 14)
    - Small-group facilitators (Box 14)
    - Statement of responsibility (Box 14)
    - Thank yous (Box 14)
    - University of Minnesota Summer Gathering housing (Box 14)
    - Video order form (Box 14)
    - Videos for gathering (Box 14)
    - Video and audio recordings, 1996; 28 items (10 VHS tapes, 10 audiocassettes, and 8 DVDs) (Box 24, Box 27, Box 28, Box 29)
    - Volunteers (Box 14)
    - Program (Box 14)
    - Photographs (Box 14)
    - General (Box 14)
    - Ageism fishbowl listening (Box 14)
    - Poster, 1996 (Box 20)
  - 1999 Gathering, B
    - African American Caucus (Box 14)
    - Alpha roster (Box 14)
    - Articles (Box 14)
    - Attendees (Box 14)
    - Banquet financial report (Box 14)
    - Banquet tickets (Box 14)
    - Bills: receipts (Box 14)
    - Bios (Box 14)
    - Brochure draft (Box 14)
    - Call for presenters (Box 14)
    - Contracts: presenters (Box 14)
    - Contract: SFSU (Box 14)
    - Correspondence (Box 14)
    - Display ad (Box 14)
    - DJ contract (Box 14)
    - Email list (Box 14)
    - Endowment fund report (Box 14)
    - Evaluation form (Box 14)
    - Evaluations (Box 15)
    - Facilitators (Box 15)
    - Facilitator guidelines (Box 15)
    - Fantasy (Box 15)
    - Gathering financial reports (Box 15)
    - Flyer (Box 15)
    - Forms and letters (Box 15)
    - Keynote address (Box 15)
    - Keynote address orders (Box 15)
    - Liability insurance (Box 15)
    - Host Committee (Box 15)
    - Letters of appreciation (Box 15)
    - Packet materials (Box 15)
    - Participant report (Box 15)
    - Presenter contracts (Box 15)
    - Press release (Box 15)
    - Program (Box 15)
    - Program ads (Box 15)
    - Registration forms (Box 15)
    - San Francisco State University (Box 15)
    - Registrants (Box 15)
    - Reports (Box 15)
    - Scholarships (Box 15)
    - Speeches (Box 15)
    - Task list (Box 15)
    - Time line (Box 15)
    - T-shirts (Box 15)
    - Video purchase (Box 15)
    - Video and audio recordings, 1999; 23 items (8 VHS tapes, 13 DVDs, and 2 audio cassette) (Box 24, Box 28, Box 29)
    - Volunteer forms (Box 15)
    - Photographs (Box 15)
    - Program (Box 15)
    - Goody Bag with pamphlets and free samples, 1999 (Box 20)
  - 2002 Gathering, C
    - Advertisers letter (Box 15)
    - Ad letter: supporter (Box 15)
    - Articles (Box 15)
    - Budget (Box 15)
    - Program (Box 15)
    - Contribution envelope (Box 15)
    - Correspondence (Box 15)
    - Courtyard arrangements (Box 15)
    - Display ad (Box 15)
    - Down Home Entertainment (Box 15)
    - Email list (Box 15)
    - Entertainment (Box 15)
    - Evaluations (Box 15)
    - Facilitators (Box 15)
    - Flyer (Box 15)
    - Fundraising letter (Box 15)
    - Gathering phone list (Box 15)
    - Schedule (Box 15)
    - Grant report (Box 15)
    - Host responsibilities (Box 15)
    - OLOC responsibilities (Box 15)
    - Packet (Box 15)
    - Panels (Box 15)
    - Press release (Box 15)
    - Program ads (Box 15)
    - Packet materials (Box 15)
    - Questionnaire (Box 15)
    - Radisson contract/menu (Box 15)
    - Registration (Box 15)
    - Registrants letter (Box 15)
    - Registration form (Box 15)
    - Reports (Box 15)
    - Scholarship (Box 15)
    - Scholarship letter (Box 15)
    - Timeline for mailings (Box 15)
    - Tobi's hard copies (Box 15)
    - T-shirts (Box 15)
    - Under 60 (Box 15)
    - Unniversity of Minnesota housing contract (Box 15)
    - Videos (Box 15)
    - Video recordings, 2002; 22 items (11 VHS tapes and 11 DVDs) (Box 25, Box 28, Box 29)
    - Program (Box 15)
    - One session workshops (Box 15)
    - Signs used at the gathering (Box 20)
    - Goody Bag with pamphlets and other handouts, 2002 (Box 20)
  - 2004 Gathering, D
    - Abstracts (Box 16)
    - ASL interpreter (Box 16)
    - Banquet intros (Box 16)
    - Bios (Box 16)
    - Bookseller (Box 16)
    - Contribution envelopes (Box 16)
    - Correspondence (Box 16)
    - DJ (Box 16)
    - Entertainment (Box 16)
    - Flyer (Box 16)
    - Fundraiser (Box 16)
    - Gathering schedule (Box 16)
    - Grant (Brenda Crawford) (Box 16)
    - Guest invitations (Box 16)
    - Hotel contract (Box 16)
    - Hotel: Renaissance Houston Hotel (Box 16)
    - Keynote speaker (Box 16)
    - Local host committee (Box 16)
    - OHP speech (Box 16)
    - OutSmart interview (Box 16)
    - Packet masters (Box 16)
    - Panels (Box 16)
    - Past advertisers (Box 16)
    - Press release (Box 16)
    - Proclamation info (Box 16)
    - Program ads (Box 16)
    - Registrations (Box 16)
    - Room assignments (Box 16)
    - Scholarship (Box 16)
    - SC progress reports (Box 16)
    - Gathering tasks (Box 16)
    - Texas ads (Box 16)
    - Texas sing-along (Box 16)
    - T-shirts (Box 16)
    - Thursday night program (Box 16)
    - Release forms (Box 16)
    - Video orders (Box 16)
    - Video recordings, 2004; 36 items (19 VHS tapes and 17 DVDs) (Box 25, Box 26, Box 28, Box 29)
    - Videographer (Box 16)
    - Programs (Box 16)
    - Photographs (Box 16)
    - Memorabilia (Box 16)
    - City of Houston Proclamation, 2004 (Box 20)
  - 2005-2014 Gatherings, E
    - National Gathering, 2005-2006 (Box 16)
    - Memorial video recordings, 2006; 1 items (1 DVD) (Box 28)
    - Regional meeting, 2007 (Box 16)
    - Gathering: general, 2008 (Box 16)
    - Gatherings, video recordings, 2008; 45 items (29 DVDs and 16 Mini DV Tape) (Box 28, Box 29)
    - Gatherings, video recording, 2010; 40 items (25 DVDs and 15 Mini DV Tapes) (Box 28, Box 29)
    - Gatherings, 2012 (Box 16)
    - Gatherings, municipal recognition, 2014 (Box 16)
  - Workshop materials, general, F
    - Why We Call Ourselve Old (Box 16)
    - Confronting Ageism workshop (Box 16, Box 20)
    - Our Life Strengths workshop (Box 16)
    - Ageism CR: finances (Box 16)
    - Workshop masters (Box 16)
  - Memorial Plaques from National Summer Gatherings (Box 19)
- Shevy Healy, 1986-2015; 3
  This series contains the professional files of Shevy Healey, one of the founders of OLOC. Materials include her speeches, workshop materials, subject files on ageism and sexism, and photographs, as well as OLOC publications, meeting minutes, and correspondence.
  - Vita (Box 17)
  - Shevy: stuff done (Box 17)
  - "Shevy's Stuff": Research, correspondence, notes (Box 17)
  - Richard Healey (Box 17)
  - Len Schneider (Box 17)
  - Shevy: correspondence and awards (Box 17)
  - Shevy: press (Box 17)
  - Speeches: correspondence (Box 17)
  - Speeches #1, 1986-1989 (Box 17)
  - Speeches #2, 1990-1992 (Box 17)
  - Danger Sheet requests (Box 17)
  - Speeches #3, 1993-1994 (Box 17)
  - Speeches #4, 1995-1999 (Box 17)
  - Speeches #5, 2000 (Box 17)
  - Speeches: multiple sclerosis (Box 17)
  - Workshops: agesism (Box 17)
  - Ageism (Box 17)
  - Ageism, Lesbian/Gay (Box 17)
  - Anti-racism (Box 17)
  - Anti-racism workshops (Box 17)
  - SAGE's Conference on Aging in the Gay and Lesbian Community, May 1-2, 1998 (Box 17)
  - Old: positive subject file (Box 17)
  - Old: negative subject file (Box 17)
  - Old: health, physical/mental (Box 17)
  - Old: working with (Box 17)
  - Alex Dobkin performance fluer, 2015 (Box 17)
  - OLOC newsletter, 1999-2008 (Box 17)
  - Contribution to Morris Kight (Box 17)
  - Sean Cahill, et al, Outing Age: Public Policy Issues Affecting Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual and Transgendered Elders, 2000 (Box 17)
  - Photographs: Shevy Healy, Ruth Silver, and others, 1990s (Box 17, Box 20)
  - Women: sexism (Box 17)
  - Women's history/herstory (Box 18)
  - OLOC Reporter: to write (Box 18)
  - OLOC Reporter and newspaper clippings, 1997-2001 (Box 18)
  - OLOC Reporter: stories sent (Box 18)
  - OLOC correspondence, 1991-2001 (Box 18)
  - OLOC: handbook, brochures (Box 18)
  - OLOC gathering, 1996 (Box 18)
  - OLOC gathering, 1999 (Box 18)
  - Facilitator's Handbook: Confronting Ageism, 1992 (Box 18)
  - OLOC Steering Committee meeting minutes and mailing list, 1996 (Box 18)